Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen General Chairman, Boston and Maine Railroad Records 5475
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen General Chairman, Boston and Maine Railroad Records
1913-1971
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen (BLF&E
Boston and Maine Railroad (B&E
5475
9 cubic feet
9 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Records, reports, committee minutes, correspondece and miscellaneous.
5652960
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 08, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 13, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen was founded on December 1, 1873, at Port Jervis, New York, to provide mutual support for railroad firemen. The Brotherhood initially emphasized insurance, but by the late nineteenth century had branched out into labor-management relations.
At the turn of the century, the organization changed its name to the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen (BLFE) after permitting engineers to join its ranks. In 1969, the union merged with the Order of Railway Conductors and Brakemen, the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, and the Switchmen's Union of North America to form the United Transportation Union.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5141: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Records 5141 G: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Graphics 5141 MB: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Memorabilia 5176: Grand Lodge of the Ladies Society of the Former Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Records 5467: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Local 807 (Auburn, NY) Records 5611: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Honorary Register of Disabled 5646: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Additional Records 5869: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Local 807 (Auburn, NY) Additional Records 6176: Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen Additional Records
Railroads--Employees--Labor unions--United States.; Collective bargaining--Railroads--United States.; Arbitration, Industrial--United States.; Railroads--United States.; Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen.; Boston and Maine Railroad.; Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen.
5652960
- H.E. Gilbert - Inter-Pres., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Claims on Grand Lodge Docket - H.S. Osborne Correspondence, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- D.B. Robinson (Box 1, Folder 3)
- W.H. Gilfoil Vice Pres. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Jonas McBride Vice Pres. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- W.H. Gilford, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- W.W. Watson Organizer (Box 1, Folder 7)
- W.W. Watson Nat. Organizer (Box 1, Folder 8)
- National Legislative - Rep. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Editor - Manager - Magazine (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Sec. and Treasurer (Box 1, Folder 11)
- M.L. Mellett - VP (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Mr. Porch (Box 1, Folder 13)
- 37th Convention (Box 1, Folder 14)
- 1963 Convention (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Railroad Adjustment Board - General (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Instructions - 1st Div. - NRAB (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Board of Trustee's (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Bd. Of Trustees (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Board of Trustees, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Board of Trustees, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Secretary - Treasurer (Box 1, Folder 22)
- G.G.C. Sec.-Treas. Quarterly Reports 1909 to 1934, 1909-1934 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- G.G.C. Sec. -Treas. Quarterly Reports Jan.1, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Agenda - GGC - Meeting, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Scope and Contents
  February 3, 1959
- Financial Reports - Quarterly - W.F. Hartford G.G.C., 1955-1959 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- G.G.C. Meeting Feb. 1963 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Board of Trustees - Elected 1963 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Joint Co-Operative Board B&M Association of Gen. Chairmen (Box 1, Folder 29)
- General Officials (Box 1, Folder 30)
- By Laws of Committee (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Association General Chairmen District No. 2 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Gen.. Grievance Comm. - District #2 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- F.L. Davis Mechanics (Box 2, Folder 1)
- F.H. Parker (Box 2, Folder 2)
- F.H. Parker (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Mr. McElroy (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Paul C. Dunn (Box 2, Folder 5)
- C.A. Come Supt. Port. Div. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Dr. Knowles Chief Surgeon (Box 2, Folder 7)
- B. of R.T. and O.R.C. (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Engineers Claims and Spare Rules (Box 2, Folder 9)
- General Comm. 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Examinations, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- A.W. Maloy Supt. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- B.G. Jones Chief Clerk (Box 2, Folder 13)
- I.C. Blodgett Supervisor of Sced. (Box 2, Folder 14)
- I.C. Blodgett Supervisor of Sced. (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Mr. Prindall M.M. (Box 2, Folder 16)
- E.C. Cone M.M. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- E.C. Hopkins - B.L.E. - Correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 18)
- C.A. Came Supt. Portland Div. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- P.C. Dunn (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Paul C. Dunn Supt. Locomotive Maintenance (Box 2, Folder 21)
- B.G. Jones - Chief Clerk (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Space Rule (Box 2, Folder 23)
- A.W. Maloy (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Examinations Fitchburg Div. (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Examinations New Hamp. Div. (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Examinations Portland Div. (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Mr. Ferguson (Box 2, Folder 28)
- J.R. Knowles M.D. - Chief Surgeon (Box 2, Folder 29)
- 99C Dec. 10 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Y.M.C.A. (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Canal Street Associates (Box 2, Folder 32)
- G.G.C. Cases to be Handled by G.G.C. (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Final Examinations 1945-1947 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Yards All Divisions (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Passes (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Bunk Rooms (Box 3, Folder 3)
- BLF & E -BLS - Organization - Correspondence and Data (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Vacations - Carrier Correspondence (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Hold for Decision of B of PJ (Box 3, Folder 6)
- T.H. Harrison Back Time / Personal Letters (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Vacations - Grand Lodge (Box 3, Folder 8)
- I. Special (Box 3, Folder 9)
- G.G.C. - 1965 Postponement (Box 3, Folder 10)
- 1959 Rules Movement - Proposed Mediation Agreement Ratified 1964 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Wage and Rules Movement 1963 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Information and Education Program (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Sentimental Folder (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Social Agreement Yard Switchers Boston (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Rules Movement 1959 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- G.C.A. Elections (Box 3, Folder 17)
- MAP - Membership Action Program (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Rules Movement Strike Instructions (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Strikes (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Military Service (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Strike Correspondence and Memorabilia (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Senate Committee (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Firemen Affected by Arb. Award (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Accidents - One Man Operation Misc. (Box 4, Folder 4)
- BLE Agreement (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Horse Crews - Memo of Understanding (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Engineers - Arb-Award Settlement - Notice 10/1/1953 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Change in Run's (Box 4, Folder 8)
- BLE Agreement 1955 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- J.A. McKinnon -Age- E-64 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Engineer Claims (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Age Limit - Firemen and Hostlers (Box 4, Folder 12)
- New Schedule 1949 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Self-Propelled Equipment (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Locomotive Class Book - 1944 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Not Qualified - Deisel (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Gen. Comm. Assoc. B&M (Box 5, Folder 1)
- G.G.C. New Lodges (Box 5, Folder 2)
- G.G.C. Sec-Trea-Report (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Association Gen. Grievance Committee (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Sec-Treas. E.H. Hart 1953-1955 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Agenda Meeting, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Feb. 5-7
- Agenda - Feb - 1955 GGC, 1955-1953 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Secretary - Treasurer's Reports (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Attend SoCal Lodge Meetings (Box 5, Folder 9)
- G.G.C. Referendum Vote for G.C. (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Misc. Circular Letters (G.L.) 1949 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Postponing - Setting Ahead Meetings G.G.C. (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Grand Lodge Bulletins (Box 5, Folder 13)
- District #2 - Buffalo - May (Box 5, Folder 14)
- H.E. Gilbert - Int. Pres. 1955 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- GCA, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Safety Awards - B&M (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Decisions as Signed (Box 5, Folder 18)
- State Legislative - Rep. (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Abandonment - Concord - Woodsville (Box 5, Folder 20)
- NRAB - 1st Division (Box 5, Folder 21)
- I.C.C. - Train Abandonments (Box 5, Folder 22)
- I.C.C. Locomotive Investigation (Box 5, Folder 23)
- General Chairmen's Reports, 1919-1921 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- General Chairmen's Reports, 1922-1924 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- General Chairmen's Reports, 1928-1930 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- General Grievance Committees Meetings, 1913-1922 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- General Chairmen's Reports, 1934-1936 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- General Grievance Committee Meetings, 1901-1912 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- General Chairmen's Report, 1937-1939 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- General Chairmen's Report (Box 6, Folder 8)
- General Chairmen's Report, 1945-1946 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- General Chairmen's Reports, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- General Chairman's Reports, 1954-1956 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Jan. 1954 - Dec. 1956
- McNamara (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Courchene Discipline (Morse) (Box 7, Folder 2)
- E.H. Smedberg Discipline (Box 7, Folder 3)
- E.H. Smedberg Discipline (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Hostlee Territory (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Courchene (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Amalgamation (Box 7, Folder 7)
- I.C.C. Reports B&M Accidents (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Union - Shop - Negotiating (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Goyer Case (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Sturtevant (Box 7, Folder 11)
- L.W. Sturtevant Discipline (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Discipline - J.F. Abbott (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Discipline Cases (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Sturtevant - Discipline (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Safety Awards (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Discipline - M.J. Healy (Box 7, Folder 17)
- J.E. Dionne - Discipline (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Spare Boards - 1915 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Personal Injury Claims (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Hall (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Foreign Railroads (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Reid, Silva (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Mr. Clark (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Scanlon J.L. - BRT (Box 8, Folder 5)
- B.F. Traverse B of R.T. (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Rutland Railway Strike (Box 8, Folder 7)
- M.L. Charity (Box 8, Folder 8)
- M.L. Mellett (Box 8, Folder 9)
- General Chairmen Other Roads (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Mr. Twitchell (Box 8, Folder 11)
- A.H. Slader (Box 8, Folder 12)
- E.M. Flagg (Box 8, Folder 13)
- W.H. Holland (Box 8, Folder 14)
- W.M. Watson (Box 8, Folder 15)
- H.D. Ulrich (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Mr. Baker (Assist. Gen. Mgr.) (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Slader - Hotel (Box 8, Folder 18)
- F.W. Rourke - Discipline (Box 8, Folder 19)
- R.W. Pickard (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Mr. McFarland M.M. (Box 8, Folder 21)
- E.K. Bloss Mechan. Super. (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Mr. Hammond (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Mechanical Exam (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Men Disqualified by Dr. Knowles (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Five-Day-Job (Box 8, Folder 26)
- General Chairmen - Other Roads (Box 8, Folder 27)
- E.H. Burney M.M. (Box 8, Folder 28)
- 5 day of requests (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Claims - IW Brackett (Box 8, Folder 30)
- Inter Division - Misc. Correspondence. (Box 8, Folder 31)
- Schedule Revision - 1955 (Box 8, Folder 32)
- D.L. Ellingwood (Box 8, Folder 33)
- Correspondence Claims (Box 8, Folder 34)
- Mr. Barrett (Box 8, Folder 35)
- Bracket and Ahearne (Box 8, Folder 36)
- Mr. Hammond (Box 8, Folder 37)
- E.K. Bloss (Box 8, Folder 38)
- Mr. McFarland (Box 8, Folder 39)
- Mr. Ferguson (Box 8, Folder 40)
- Mr. Barrett (Box 8, Folder 41)
- Mr. Slader (Box 8, Folder 42)
- Mr. Clark (Box 8, Folder 43)
- Mrs. Rourke (Box 8, Folder 44)
- Mr. Baker (Assist. Gen. Manager) (Box 8, Folder 45)
- Mr. Twitchell B. of L.E. (Box 8, Folder 46)
- Travers (Box 8, Folder 47)
- Mr. Hall Chief of Personnel (Box 8, Folder 48)
- Prindall - Cone - McElroy (Box 8, Folder 49)
- Arbitration Between the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen and the Eastern Railroads (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Arbitration between the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen and the Eastern Railroads (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Arbitration between the Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen and the Eastern Railroads, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 3)